SHE'S BEEN RUNNING
INTELLIGENCE DOWN IN FRESNO.NEW BOSS?
NEW BOSS.
MADELEINE HIGHTOWER.
CHIEF DEPUTY A.G. SAYS SHE'LL
BE HERE SOMETIME TOMORROW.
WORD IS
SHE'S HARD AS NAILS--
POLITICAL,
TIGHT STATEHOUSE CONNECTIONS.SO THIS IS GOOD FOR US.
WE'LL HAVE
SOME REAL MUSCLE UPSTAIRS.WE'LL SEE.
NO NEED TO BE NERVOUS.
I'M NOT NERVOUS.
YOU'RE AN EXEMPLARY AGENT.
NO REASON FOR BUTTERFLIES.
NO BUTTERFLIES.
I'M FINE.
KEEP TELLING YOURSELF
THAT.
HOW YA DOING?
VIC BANDINO, ALPHA BRAVO
RESIDENTIAL SECURITY.
APPRECIATE
YOUR QUICK RESPONSE.AGENT LISBON.
THIS IS PATRICK JANE,
AND THIS IS AG--
WAYNE RIGSBY. CBI, HUH?
YOU DID OKAY. [laughs]HI, BANDINO. WHAT'S UP?
[chuckles]
WE WORKED A COUPLE OF CASES
TOGETHER BACK IN THE DAY.
SAN DIEGO P.D. ARSON SQUAD.[chuckles] YEAH. BOY,
THOSE WERE THE TIMES, HUH?
REMEMBER THAT STAKEOUT
IN PISMO?YOU EVER CALL THAT CHICK?
YEAH--WOULD YOU SHOW US
THE BODY, MR. BANDINO?
YES, MA'AM.
YEAH, OF COURSE. PLEASE.
HE'S IN THE POOL HOUSE.
NAME'S JAMES SMITHSON--
28, BRITISH CITIZEN.
HE'S A HIGH-PRICED TUTOR
FOR LOCAL KIDS.
DAUGHTER OF THE HOMEOWNER'S
ONE OF THE STUDENTS.
COUPLE MONTHS AGO
THEY LET HIM MOVE IN HERE.
RIGSBY, CAN YOU FIND OUT
WHY THE CORONER'S NOT HERE?[Rigsby] YEAH, SURE.
WHO FOUND THE BODY? YOU?
THE HOMEOWNER'S KID.
SHE WAS COMING IN FOR A LESSON.
[sighs] SHE CALLED HER DAD.
HE CALLED ME. I CALLED YOU.NOT THE LOCAL POLICE?
WHY US EXACTLY?
I DON'T KN--WHAT THE HELL, VIC?
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO CALL ME
THE SECOND THEY GOT HERE.EXCUSE ME, SIR?
I'M HOPPER BANKS.AGENT LISBON, CBI.
THIS IS A CRIME SCENE.
[Hopper] IT'S MY PLACE.
MR. BANKS, I NEED YOU TO LEAVE.
CAN YOU DO THAT FOR ME?
I'LL BE IN THE MAIN HOUSE.
I'LL EXPECT A FULL REPORT.
THAT'S WHY I CALLED YOU.
OLD CALIFORNIA MONEY,
LOTS OF CLOUT.
LOCAL P.D. WON'T CUT IT.
HE WANTS THE BEST.
CORONER'S ON HIS WAY.A SINGLE GUNSHOT.
JUDGING BY THE WOUND,
LOOKS LIKE A .38. NO WEAPON.
DON'T WORRY.
IT'S A VISUAL INSPECTION.
DIDN'T TOUCH A THING.
[Lisbon] NO SIGN
OF ASSAULT OR ROBBERY?
REAL FANCY RéSUMé,
THIS GUY.
GRADUATED
FROM ETON AND OXFORD.
LAST EMPLOYER WAS SOME
HOTSHOT PREP SCHOOL BACK EAST.
MEH,
I WOULDN'T BE SO SURE.
EXCUSE ME?THE FACIAL SCAR.
ETON BOY GETS A CUT ON HIS HEAD,
AND HE NEEDS A PLASTIC SURGEON,
HE GETS A PLASTIC SURGEON.
MY GUESS--THE WHOLE RéSUMé
IS A FAIRY TALE.
EXCUSE ME?YOU'RE EXCUSED.
I CHECKED HIM OUT MYSELF.WELL, I'M WRONG THEN.
UH... NO BLISTERS
OR CALLUSES ON HIS HANDS.
A LOT OF DIRT
UNDER HIS FINGERNAILS.
[Vic] WHO IS THIS GUY?[Rigsby] IT'S A LONG STORY.
[sniffs] HMM.[Lisbon] ANYTHING ELSE?
[Vic] I GOT THE CALL
AT 3:35.
I WAS AT
A CLIENT'S RESIDENCE NEARBY,
WORKING AN ALARM UPGRADE.
ARRIVED HERE AT 3:52.
BODY WAS STILL WARM,
SO I GUESS THE TIME OF DEATH WAS
A GOOD HOUR BEFORE THAT.
[gasps]
GUESS AGAIN.
[police radio chatter]
IT'S CALLED
LAZARUS SYNDROME.
GUY'S HEART SOMEHOW CAUGHT
AN ELECTRICAL CHARGE
AND RESTARTED.
HEY, IT HAPPENS.
SO YOU'RE SAYING HE'S ALIVE?WELL, IF YOU CAN CALL THAT
LIVING. HE'S BRAIN-DEAD.
WITH NO OXYGEN
FOR MORE THAN TEN MINUTES,
HE'S NOT COMING BACK.THERE'S SECURITY CAMERAS
OUT THERE.
HAVE BANDINO SHOW YOU
THE FOOTAGE.
MAYBE WE'LL GET LUCKY
AND CATCH A LOOK AT THE SHOOTER.
I NEED TO GO
AND TALK TO THE LITTLE GIRL
WHO FOUND THE BODY.YOU GOT IT.
[rustling]
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING FOR?
THE DIRT UNDER HIS NAILS
SMELLED LIKE ROSEMARY.
YEAH.
WHATEVER WAS INSIDE THIS BOX
KILLED OUR MAN.
WELL, THE CASE IS
PRACTICALLY CLOSED.
THERE'S NO REASON TO BE
SNARKY.
IT WAS MY WIFE JOLENE,
REALLY.
SHE SAW HOW MUCH JAMES HELPED
LANIE WITH HER SCHOOLWORK,
AND WHEN SHE HEARD
HE NEEDED A PLACE TO LIVE,
SHE RENTED THE POOL HOUSE
TO HIM.
I GUESS HE'S BEEN HERE,
UH...
I DON'T KNOW.
A COUPLE OF MONTHS, MAYBE.
VERY GENEROUS
OF YOUR WIFE.
JOLENE HAS A BIG HEART.
IS THIS HER?
MY MUSE.
GOOD-LOOKING. MM.
SHE TURNED ME
INTO A REAL ARTIST.
BEFORE I MET HER,
I WAS TAKING SNAPSHOTS.
MR. BANKS, WE'RE GONNA NEED
TO TALK TO YOUR DAUGHTER.
I'M SORRY. LANIE'S TOO UPSET
TO TALK AT THE MOMENT.
PLEASE. MAYBE LATER.
WE NEED TO SPEAK TO HER
WHEN HER MEMORY'S FRESH.SHE SAW WHAT YOU SAW.
SHE CAME HOME,
WENT TO THE POOL HOUSE
FOR SOME HOMEWORK HELP...WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO HEAR THAT FROM HER.
AND SHE FOUND A DEAD BODY.
SHE'S 12 YEARS OLD.
DON'T--DON'T YOU GET IT?
IT'S NOT HOMEWORK. IT'S
A PROJECT ABOUT THE PYRAMIDS.
I CAN TALK TO YOU.THANKS, LANIE.
SIT RIGHT HERE, SWEETIE.
I'M AGENT LISBON,
AND THAT'S PATRICK JANE.
HI. WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO DO
FOR THE PYRAMID PROJECT?
DESCRIBE THE AFTERLIFE
AS DEPICTED IN
THE ANCIENT EGYPTIAN MYTHOLOGY.
AH, AS DEPICTED IN
WELL, DID YOU KNOW THAT
THEY BELIEVED THAT WHEN YOU DIE,
YOU ARE CARRIED
INTO THE NEXT LIFE
ON THE BACK
OF A SACRED HIPPOPOTAMUS?
THAT'S TRUE.
WHAT TIME DID YOU GET HOME
FROM SCHOOL?
A LITTLE AFTER 3:00.WHAT DID YOU DO?
I MADE LEMONADE.
JAMES LOVES MY LEMONADE.
WHO ELSE WAS HOME?
UH, NOBODY. UH,
I WAS AT THE GALLERY,
AND JOLENE WAS AT THE GYM.[Lisbon]
MR. BANKS, PLEASE.
[Lanie] NO ONE WAS HERE.
I TOOK THE LEMONADE
TO THE POOL HOUSE.
I-I SAW...
[voice breaking]
SO MUCH BLOOD.
DID YOU SEE ANYBODY
OR HEAR ANYTHING?
VOICES? A CAR?
[crying] JUST JAMES.I'M TAKING HER
UPSTAIRS NOW.
DOES ANYBODY KNOW
WHAT WAS INSIDE THIS?
NO. ARE WE THROUGH?ALMOST.
LANIE, WHY DIDN'T YOUR MOTHER
WANT YOU TO SPEAK TO US?
SHE'S NOT MY MOTHER.
HONEY, IT--IT'S OKAY.
I WAS PROTECTING HER.
SHE'S BEEN THROUGH
A VERY TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE.
OH, I THOUGHT YOU WERE WORRIED
SHE WAS GONNA SAY SOMETHING
ABOUT WHATEVER IT IS YOU'RE
TRYING TO HIDE FROM US.
HOW DARE YOU?
REALLY? HOW DAREI?
IS THAT THE BEST COMEBACK
YOU'VE GOT?
YOU'RE GONNA LET THIS MAN
INSULT ME?HUH?
STAND THERE WITH
YOUR MOUTH OPEN LIKE A MORON.
BABY.[glass clanks]
BABY. REALLY?
WHEW. WELL PLAYED.
YEAH. I'M STARVING.
WE'VE GOT FOUR CAMERAS
IN THE BACKYARD.
WE RAN THE FOOTAGE
FROM SUNUP TILL WE GOT HERE.CHECK THIS OUT.
[tapping keys]WE FOUND THIS AT 2:37.
WATCH THE WINDOW.
IT'S A MUZZLE FLASH.WHO'S IN THERE?
WH-WHAT CAMERA HAD THE DOOR?
THIS IS THE ONLY IMAGE
WE'VE GOT.
NOBODY COMING IN OR OUT
OR IN THE YARD?
[mouth full]
WHOEVER SHOT SMITHSON KNEW
WHERE THOSE CAMERAS WERE PLACED
AND HOW TO AVOID 'EM.
THIS ONE'S MINE. IF YOU WANT
ONE, I CAN MAKE ONE FOR YOU.
WE NEED TO CHECK
JOLENE AND HOPPER'S ALIBIS.
YOU KNOW,
HOLD ON A SECOND.
NONE OF THESE CAMERAS ARE
HIDDEN.
ANYONE CAN SEE 'EM--
GUESTS,
STUDENTS COMING HERE
FOR TUTORING, THEIR PARENTS,
EVERYBODY.OH. GOOD POINT.
THANKS FOR YOUR TIME,
MR. BANDINO.
THANK YOU.
CHEERS.
[Van Pelt] THE VICTIM,
JAMES SMITHSON, DOESN'T EXIST.
PASSPORT'S FAKE.
HIS REFERENCES ARE BOGUS.
I RAN HIS PRINTS
THROUGH ALL THE DATABASES.
THERE'S NOTHING,
NOTHING AT ALL.
YOUR FRIEND BANDINO DIDN'T DO
MUCH OF A BACKGROUND CHECK.
MM. THAT'S NOT LIKE HIM.
HE'S NOT THE SHARPEST KNIFE
IN THE DRAWER,
BUT HE ALWAYS DID
THE LEGWORK.DO YOU THINK MAYBE HE'S
HOLDING SOMETHING BACK,
PROTECTING HIS CLIENTS?YEAH, I'LL CHECK IT OUT.
TAKE VAN PELT.
[sighs]
JUST STOP WORRYING.
IT'S GONNA BE FINE
WITH THE NEW BOSS.
I MEAN, SURE, THERE'LL BE
A SETTLING-IN PERIOD
WHEN SHE PROBES YOUR PSYCHE
FOR WEAKNESS,
BUT ONCE THAT'S
OUT OF THE WAY--WOULD YOU STOP?
YOU'RE BEING SO CHILDISH.
I THINK YOU'RE
THE ONE WHO'S NERVOUS.
OOH. THAT SOUNDS PERCEPTIVE.
LET ME THINK ABOUT THAT.
NO. I FIND THAT I'M NOT.
IT'S DEFINITELY YOU.
I'M GONNA GO TALK
TO SMITHSON'S REGULAR STUDENTS
AND THEIR PARENTS,
FILL IN SOME OF THESE BLANKS.GOOD IDEA.
TAKE HIM WITH YOU.
[Cho] COME ON.
[woman] MY GOD.
IT'S SO TERRIBLE.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO DID IT?
WE'RE STILL INVESTIGATING,
MRS. BLANKMAN.
NOW THE PARENTS AND STUDENTS
WE'VE TALKED TO ALL SAY
HE WAS A GREAT TUTOR,
BUT NOT MUCH ELSE.
HOW WELL DID YOU KNOW
MR. SMITHSON?
NOT THAT WELL.
JAMES HAD ONLY BEEN TUTORING
MY SON FOR...
THREE... FOUR MONTHS.
I'D DROP OFF, PICK UP.
YOU KNOW, SAY HELLO.
HE SEEMED NICE.
E-EXCUSE ME,
MRS. BLANKMAN.
I-I'M SORRY.
DON'T MEAN TO INTERRUPT.
I'M A LITTLE PARCHED.
COULD I BOTHER YOU
FOR A CUP OF TEA?
OH. I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T OFFER YOU--OH, N-N-NO, PLEASE.
I-I CAN GET IT.
YOU'RE SHAKING.
WOULD YOU LIKE A CUP?
UH...CHO?
NO, THANKS.
[sniffs]
[kettle whistling]
[closes cabinet doors]
[spritzing]
YOUR SON NEVER MENTIONED
ANYTHING?
MONEY PROBLEMS?
ANYTHING UNUSUAL?
THEY JUST STUDIED.
SMELLED SO GOOD,
I WENT AND MADE YOU ONE.
LEMONGRASS, MY FAVORITE.
[sighs]
YEAH, IT'S FUNNY
HOW SMELLS WORK.
THEY ATTACH THEMSELVES
TO SUCH SPECIFIC MEMORIES.
YOU KNOW, LIKE THE, UH,
KITCHEN OF A CHILDHOOD HOME,
OR HAVING A CUP OF TEA
WITH A LOVER.
[inhales and exhales deeply]
[whispers] YES.
YES.
YES,
YOU AND JAMES WERE LOVERS.
[voice breaking] YES.
MM-HMM.
OH, YOU MIGHT NOT WANT
TO DRINK THAT.
THAT'S
A LITTLE... FUNKY MONKEY.[gasps]
WHAT KIND OF BACKGROUND CHECK
DID YOU DO, VIC?
[Vic] THE USUAL.
I CALLED HIS LAST EMPLOYER.
I CHECKED HIS CREDIT.WELL, JAMES SMITHSON ISN'T
JAMES SMITHSON.
NONE OF IT'S TRUE.WELL, THERE'S A LIMIT
TO WHAT I CAN DO, YOU KNOW?
I'M NOT THE CIA, HERE.AW, COME ON, MAN. YOU USED
TO BE MORE GUNG-HO THAN THAT.
[laughs] THAT'S
WHY I'M NOT A COP ANYMORE.
IT'S TOO STRESSFUL.
UNHEALTHY PROFESSION.
YEAH, NO KIDDING.
HEY, YOU GOT ANYTHING?
SERIOUSLY, YOU HEAR
ABOUT HANK HARRISON?
39 YEARS OLD,
5 YEARS OUT FROM HIS PENSION--
BOOM. HEART ATTACK.
A WIFE, TWO KIDS.
HE HAD THAT, UH,
THAT BACHELOR PARTY, REMEMBER?
UH, NO.
AW, COME ON.
SURE YOU DO.
THE STRIPPER WAS ALL OVER
HIS CASE, I'M TELLING YA.
I BET SHE WAS.
OH. [laughs] OH, HEY.
ARE YOU TWO, LIKE, UH--
ARE YOU DATING EACH OTHER?
NO, WE'RE NOT.NO.
NO? BECAUSE YOU BOTH LOOKED
A LITTLE WEIRD JUST NOW.NO.
WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT A MURDER HERE.
YEAH. YEAH, HEY, LOOK,
I'M SORRY, ALL RIGHT?
UH, THERE IS ONE THING.
A COUPLE MONTHS AGO, HOPPER WAS
WORKING ON THIS PHOTO THING.
HE, UH--HE ASKED ME
TO GET HIM A GUN.
OLD-FASHIONED PIECE,
LIKE THE FBI WAS USING
IN SOME '60s MOVIE HE SAW.LIKE A .38?
YEAH, I GUESS.
WE NEVER GOT TO THAT.
I TURNED HIM DOWN.
TOLD HIM IF HE WANTED IT
LIKE THE MOVIE, GET A PROP GUN.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HE DID IN THE END,
BUT IT'S WORTH MENTIONING,
RIGHT?YEAH. YEAH, IT IS.
THANKS, MAN. APPRECIATE IT.
HEY, ABSOLUTELY.THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
YEAH, NO PROBLEM.
HEY, LISTEN.
WHAT SAY YOU AND ME GO GET A CUP
OF COFFEE SOME TIME? [chuckles]NO, THANKS.
HUH? WHAT'S COFFEE?
I'M A NICE GUY, RIGHT, RIGS?
SEE YA LATER, VIC.
[Cho] SO SMITHSON WAS
A BIG LADIES' MAN,
AND THEY'VE BOTH GOT
SOLID ALIBIS.
MAGGIE BLANKMAN'S HUSBAND'S BEEN
IN RENO FOR THE LAST THREE DAYS,
AND MAGGIE WAS
AT A THERAPIST'S SESSION
FROM 2:00 TO 4:00 P.M.--
DOUBLE SESSION.JANE AND I ARE GONNA GO
TO HOPPER'S GALLERY,
ASK ABOUT THE GUN.
[exhales deeply]
HEY. [sighs]
[tapping keys]
WANT A COFFEE?
NO, THANKS.
SO WHAT WAS HER NAME?
WHO?
THE STRIPPER.
O-OH. I, UH...
WE COULD DOUBLE-DATE--
ME AND BANDINO,
YOU AND YOUR STRIPPER.
WH--I TH--
I THOUGHT Y-YOU...
[laughs]
OH. [laughs]
THAT'S MEAN.
KIDDING.
OH, HER NAME WAS,
UH, KANDY.
OH, YEAH.
SWEET KANDY, WITH A "K."
[singsongy] OH.
[normal voice]
KANDY WITH A "K." MM-HMM.[typing]
DO I OWN A GUN?
YES, MR. BANKS, A .38.[sighs]
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN IN
POSSESSION OF ONE OR OWNED ONE?
I NEVER HAD A GUN,
ANY KIND.
I DON'T BELIEVE IN THEM.
YOU'RE JUST NOT TRYING
HARD ENOUGH.
I AM. YOU JUST
CAN'T READ MINDS.
YOU CLOSE YOUR EYES, OKAY?
I'M THE BOSS HERE.
CONCENTRATE.
IT'S COMING TO ME.
CHOCOLATE...
COCONUT...
SWIRL. HUH?
VANILLA.
PAY UP.
THAT'S NOT FUNNY.
[laughs] YEAH, IT IS. HEY,
DAD, JUST GETTING ICE CREAM.
OKAY.
UH, WOULD YOU MIND
TAKING A POLYGRAPH TEST?
NO. WHY WOULD I DO THAT?
I'LL GIVE YOU THIS,
HOPPER--
YOU HAVE
A VERY CONSISTENT VISION.
A LITTLE CRAZY,
BUT CONSISTENT.
[Hopper] I WOULDN'T EXPECT YOU
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT I'M DOING.
LET ME GIVE IT A SHOT.
YOU ENJOY TAKING POSSESSION
OF YOUR WIFE,
BUT ONLY ON CAMERA,
NOT IN THE FLESH.
YOU WERE BEING CUCKOLDED
BY JAMES SMITHSON,
AND YOU LET IT HAPPEN.
WHY?
IMPOTENCE? MASOCHISM?
HOMOSEXUALITY?
I'M NOT SURE.
[laughs] THAT'S VERY PERCEPTIVE,
MR. JANE. YOU HAVE A TALENT.
MEH, IT'S JUST...
I DO. THANKS.
IT'S JUST...
IT'S AN EASY CALL.
YOU'RE VERY ATTRACTIVE
BUT UNHAPPY
AND ACCUSTOMED TO USING
YOUR SEXUALITY AS A WEAPON.
DID YOU USE YOUR SEXUALITY
AS A WEAPON AGAINST HIM?
OKAY, YOU'RE DONE.
NOW... GO.
WHAT DOES IT TAKE
TO GET YOU MAD, HOPPER?
DID SMITHSON RUB YOUR NOSE
IN IT?THAT'S RIDICULOUS!
WHAT'S WRONG?
UH, NOTHING, HONEY. UH,
THESE PEOPLE WERE JUST LEAVING.YEAH, WE SHOULD LEAVE.
LET'S. YEAH.
OKAY.
HOW'S THE ICE CREAM?GOOD.
YEAH.
HARD TO BEAT VANILLA.
[Lisbon] I KNOW, I KNOW.
YOU WERE MAKING STUFF UP
TO GET THE GUY ANGRY
SO YOU COULD GET A READ
ON HIM. BLAH, BLAH, BLAH.
THE TRUTH IS,
YOU JUST DIDN'T LIKE THE GUY.
WELL, THAT WOULD BE
VERY UNPROFESSIONAL.
UM, COULD YOU TAKE
THE NEXT LEFT, PLEASE?
OKAY.
WELL, WHAT DID YOU READ?
DID HE DO IT?
TAKE THE NEXT LEFT,
AND I'LL TELL YOU.
WELL?
WELL, MAYBE.
HE HAD A GOOD MOTIVE.
AND MAYBE NOT.
THE RED BOX DIDN'T FIT.
YOU PICKED UP A TAIL?
CUL-DE-SAC.
[turns off engine]
[sighs]
NOTHING.
YOU SURE?
UH-HUH.
EXCUSE ME.
WHY ARE YOU FOLLOWING US?
[Southern accent]
FOLLOWING YOU?
SHOOT, I THOUGHT
CALIFORNIA WAS FRIENDLY.
I'M JUST TRYING TO MAKE
A SALE HERE--LIFE INSURANCE.
CUTE YOUNG COUPLE
LIKE YOURSELVES,
NOW YOU'VE GOTTA THINK
ABOUT THE FUTURE, RIGHT?
YOU GOT KIDS YET?
THAT'S A TERRIBLE ACCENT.
DISGUISED BRITISH, YES?
YOU GOTTA WORK ON
YOUR GLOTTAL STOP.
HIS WHAT?[mouth full]
HIS GLOTTAL STOP.
CAN WE SEE
SOME IDENTIFICATION, PLEASE?
UH, SURE. IT'S IN THE CAR.
I'LL--HOLD ON, I'LL GET IT.UH-OH.
PUT YOUR HANDS ON THE CAR.
NOW.
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
TURN AROUND.
A STRANGER ASKS TO SEE
YOUR I.D.,
YOU ASK THEM
TO SHOW YOU THEIRS FIRST.
UNLESS, OF COURSE, YOU'RE
TRYING TO HIDE SOMETHING.
[British accent] QUITE RIGHT.
QUITE RIGHT, MR. JANE.
[chuckles]
WHO ARE YOU?
[sighs] FRANCIS SLOCOMBE.
INSPECTOR FRANCIS SLOCOMBE.
SCOTLAND YARD
SPECIAL BRANCH.
EH.
[crunches]
[Cho] THANK YOU.
[hangs up telephone receiver]
I CAN'T REACH YOUR CONTACT
AT SCOTLAND YARD.
TIME DIFFERENCE.
TRICKY ONE, THAT.
YEP, FRANCIS SLOCOMBE,
REGISTERED
AT THE FLAMINGO HOTEL.
WHERE'S JANE?HERE.
OH, THANKS. LOVELY.
DID YOU CHECK LIVERPOOL'S SCORE?UP 1-NOTHING.
END OF THE FIRST HALF.
EXCELLENT.
WHERE ARE
THE CUCUMBER SANDWICHES?
I'M BEING NICE TO HIM,
BECAUSE I THINK HE MIGHT KNOW
WHAT WAS IN THIS.OH, WHAT ABOUT
OUR SEARCH WARRANT
THAT GOT KILLED?
FOR THE MURDER WEAPON?YOU'RE NOT EVEN
A BIT CURIOUS?
AFTER YOUR PERFORMANCE
AT THE GALLERY,
BANKS MADE
SOME PHONE CALLS.
NOW JUDGE WITHERS WON'T SIGN
THE WARRANT.OOPS. SORRY.
UH, SHE'S A LITTLE CRANKY.
NEW BOSS COMING IN.ENOUGH WITH THAT.
DID HIS STORY CHECK OUT?
NOPE.ABOUT JAMES SMITHSON--
HIS REAL NAME'S OLIVER STANS.
NINE MONTHS AGO HE STOLE
AN EXTREMELY VALUABLE ARTIFACT
FROM THE BRITISH MUSEUM--
A PRISTINE EXAMPLE OF
GRECO-ROMAN ART CIRCA 50 B.C.
A WEDDING RING,
SAID TO BELONG TO CLEOPATRA,
GIVEN HER BY MARK ANTONY.
THAT'S WHAT WAS IN THE BOX.
AH.
HERE'S A COPY
FROM THE MUSEUM GIFT SHOP.
STANS LIFTED THE RING
AND REPLACED IT
WITH ONE OF THOSE.
WHAT WAS HE DOING
IN THE UNITED STATES?
HE KNEW WE WERE BUILDING
A CASE AGAINST HIM.
CHANGED HIS NAME,
DISAPPEARED.
A WEEK AGO
WE PICKED UP CHATTER
THAT A DEALER
IN STOLEN ANTIQUITIES
WAS GONNA BUY THE RING HERE,
HAD SENT SOMEONE TO PICK IT UP.
MAY I?
THIS IS LOUIS ANGLET...
[clicks]GO-TO COURIER IN
THE HIGH-END STOLEN ART MARKET.
I FOLLOWED HIM HERE
TO STANS AND THE RING,
BUT I ARRIVED TOO LATE.
THAT'S WHY
I WAS FOLLOWING YOU.
[sighs]
ANGLET HAS THE RING NOW,
AND I NEED TO GET BACK
ON THE TRAIL.
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE
UNTIL YOUR STORY CHECKS OUT.
WHOEVER KILLED STANS
KILLED HIM FOR THE RING.
RON, TAKE MR. SLOCOMBE
TO AN INTERROGATION ROOM.
SIT ON HIM
WHILE I MAKE A CALL.
SURE.
[handcuffs click]
LET'S GO.
SLOCOMBE'S RIGHT.
JAMES SMITHSON IS OLIVER STANS.
A FEW MINOR ARRESTS--
NARCOTICS POSSESSION CHARGE,
ASSAULT.
LOOKS LIKE A BAR FIGHT.
[typing]
AND YES, A PERSON OF INTEREST
IN THE BRITISH MUSEUM THEFT.ANY NEXT OF KIN?
THE HOSPITAL CALLED.
THEY NEED SOMEONE TO SIGN OFF
ON ORGAN DONATION.
UH... STANS' MOTHER WAS
A SINGLE PARENT.
DIED THREE YEARS AGO.
NO SIBLINGS.
[Lisbon]
CHO, COME WITH ME.
WE NEED TO ASK SLOCOMBE
SOME QUESTIONS.
[gasps] HIS GUN'S GONE.
I'LL GET
A SEARCH STARTED.
RON, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
[groans]
FBI SAYS HE'S SCOTLAND YARD,
BUT HE'S GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS CASE.
NINE MONTHS AGO
WHEN THE RING WAS LIFTED,
HE WENT OFF THE RESERVATION.
HE'S BEEN TRACKING STANS
EVER SINCE.HMM.
YOU THINK
HE HELPED WITH THE ROBBERY,
AND STANS
DOUBLE-CROSSED HIM?NO. NO, SLOCOMBE'S JUST TRYING
TO GET THE RING BACK.
"WHY?" IS THE BIG QUESTION.
[Lisbon] YOU TWO,
GO TO HIS MOTEL ROOM.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND ANYTHING
THERE THAT'LL HELP US.OKAY.
HEY, NO SIGN OF SLOCOMBE.
I GOT A GRID SEARCH STARTED.
THIS IS PERFECT.
IT'S PERFECT.
[telephone ringing in distance]
AGENT LISBON.
MADELEINE HIGHTOWER.
SPECIAL AGENT HIGHTOWER,
WELCOME.THANK YOU.
THIS IS PATRICK JANE.
THE FAMOUS MR. JANE.
MM-HMM.
GOOD TO MEET YOU.YOU, TOO.
I THOUGHT I'D HAVE
A NICE, QUIET DAY TODAY,
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE
THERE'S TROUBLE.
WE LOST SOMEBODY.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR HIM.
THEN I'M SURE
YOU'LL FIND HIM.
LET'S TALK IN MY OFFICE.
GIVE ME A HALF-HOUR
TO ROLL SOME CALLS.
YES, MA'AM.
SHE LIKES YOU.
I CAN TELL.
[Rigsby] I'VE STAYED
IN WORSE PLACES.
THAT'S SHOCKING.[singsongy] OH.
[bed squeaking][normal voice] OH. OH, WOW.
THAT IS A GOOD BED
FOR A MOTEL ROOM. VERY FIRM.
UH-HUH.
YOU, UH... YOU WANNA TRY IT?
OH, COME ON.
WHAT? THERE'S NOBODY HERE.
WE CAN LOCK THE DOOR.
NOBODY'S LOOKING.[sighs]
COME ON.WE'RE ON DUTY.
YEAH, I KNOW.
TOTALLYWRONG.
[laughs] COME ON.
[laughs][closes drawer]
WHAT?
HOLD THAT THOUGHT.
WHAT YOU GOT?
EUREKA.
YEAH, EUREKA. NOW DOES THAT MEAN
YOU CAN GET BACK HERE?
THIS COULD BE
CRITICAL EVIDENCE.YES, IT COULD BE,
BUT UNLESS THE CRITICAL EVIDENCE
SELF-DESTRUCTS
IN LESS THAN TEN SECONDS,
I SUGGEST
YOU GET YOURSELF BACK HERE.[pats bed]
IT'S CRITICAL.
[laughs]
[giggles] FINE.
[bed squeaks]
MM. MM.MM.
[door opens]
OOH.[door creaks]
[clears throat]
ROOM'S GOOD. THANK YOU.YEAH.
[knock on door]
[Hightower] COME IN.
MA'AM, I ASSURE YOU,
TODAY'S INCIDENT IS NOT
AT ALL INDICATIVE
OF THE UNIT'S
OVERALL CONFIDENCE.
YOU HAD A BAD DAY,
AGENT LISBON.
YOU SCREWED UP.
IT HAPPENS.
NOW LET'S GET TO THE WORK.
THIS JUDGE,
THE ONE WHO CHANGED HIS MIND
ABOUT GIVING US
OUR SEARCH WARRANT--
JUDGE WITHERS, MA'AM.
HE'S KINDA LIKE
A STUBBORN OLD BULL--
WON'T BUDGE
ONCE HE TAKES A POSITION.
I'M TRYING TO GET HIM
ON THE PHONE.AND HE CHANGED HIS MIND
BECAUSE?
HE SAID WE HADN'T MET
THE THRESHOLD.
NOT WHAT HE SAID.
THE REAL REASON.
[sighs]
PATRICK JANE INSULTED
HOPPER BANKS,
AND HOPPER BANKS COMPLAINED.JANE HAS UNUSUAL METHODS,
BUT--
HE CLOSES CASES,
YES, HE DOES.
HE'S A VALUABLE ASSET.
WE CANNOT AFFORD TO LOSE HIM.
THE WAY I SEE IT...
[sighs] IT'S YOU
THAT'S IN A TRICKY SPOT.
MA'AM?
THIS BUREAU HAS SEEN
SOME TOUGH TIMES LATELY.
MY MISSION IS TO TURN THAT
AROUND AND MAKE THE CBI
THE PREMIER LAW ENFORCEMENT
AGENCY IN THIS STATE.
PATRICK JANE IS A HUGE PART
OF THAT GOAL.
IF YOU CAN'T KEEP HIM
IN LINE,
WE'LL FIND SOMEONE WHO CAN.
YES, MA'AM.
YOU CAN GO.
I'LL GIVE JUDGE WITHERS
A CALL,
GET YOU A WARRANT.
[dialing]
HEY, BOSS. ACCORDING TO
THE INFORMATION SLOCOMBE DUG UP,
LOUIS ANGLET DOESN'T JUST DEAL
IN STOLEN ANTIQUITIES.
HE'S A HIRED GUN,
NEVER INDICTED,
BUT A PRIME SUSPECT
IN THREE KILLS.
AND HE HASN'T LEFT THE COUNTRY.
HE'S STILL HERE.
MULTIPLE I.D.s, MULTIPLE
ARRESTS, BUT NO JAIL TIME.
HE'S A SLIPPERY CUSTOMER.
HE LOOKS GOOD FOR IT.WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE ANGLET IS.
WHAT WE DO KNOW IS
THAT EVERY TIME SLOCOMBE
OPENS HIS MOUTH, HE LIES.
WE'VE GOT A BOLO OUT ON HIM.
IN THE MEANTIME,
LET'S JUST PURSUE
THE CASE WE'RE DEVELOPING.
HOPPER BANKS IS STILL
OUR PRIME SUSPECT.
LET'S CHECK OUT HIS HOUSE
FOR THE GUN.
WE DON'T HAVE A SEARCH WARRANT.WE DO NOW.
HIGHTOWER GOT WITHERS
TO SIGN OFF ON IT.
HEY.HEY, ABOUT THE GUN--
DID YOU FIND ANYTHING?
IF YOU DID, I HOPE YOU KEEP
MY NAME OUT OF IT--GO AWAY, MR. BANDINO.
NOTHING SO FAR.
I GOT SOME MORE GUYS COMING.
IT'S A BIG HOUSE.AGENT LISBON, WHAT IS
THE CBI EQUIVALENT OF SIBERIA?
BECAUSE WHATEVER IT IS,
THAT'S WHERE YOU'RE GOING.HOLD THAT THOUGHT, MR. BANKS.
LOOK WHAT I FOUND
IN THE HOME OFFICE.
IT'S A PICTURE OF A PROP.IT'S A PICTURE OF A COLT,
DETECTIVE SPECIAL,
.38 CALIBER, 4-INCH BARREL--
THE SAME KIND OF GUN
KILLED OUR VICTIM.A PROP.
WHY DON'T WE SORT OUT WHICH ONE
AT OUR OFFICES, MR. BANKS?
[monitor beeping rhythmically]
[lowered voice] OH, OLIVER,
YOU IDIOT.
YOU BLOODY IDIOT.
[chair scrapes floor]
WHO'S THAT?
COME OUT OR I WILL SHOOT.
UH, I CHECKED FOR YOU.
LIVERPOOL LOST.
BAD SEASON, HUH?
INJURIES.
YOU'RE EXPECTING ME, THEN?
NICE WORK.
OH, YOU DROPPED EVERYTHING,
YOU RISKED YOUR WHOLE CAREER
TO, UH, FIND HIM BEFORE
YOUR COLLEAGUES AT THE YARD.
YOU FOLLOWED US
AFTER HE WAS SHOT.
YOU'RE BOTH LIVERPOOL FANS.
HE'S FAMILY.
YOUR SON?
YEAH.
MY SON.
I WAS NO FATHER TO HIM.
NEVER MARRIED HIS MOTHER.
NEVER SPENT TIME WITH HIM
AT ALL, REALLY.
BUT I KEPT TRACK.
I TRIED.
AND LOOK AT HIM NOW.
LOOK AT MY BOY.
HE WAS
A BRILLIANT YOUNG MAN.
FROM NOTHING,
UNDER HIS OWN STEAM,
HE GOT HIMSELF A SCHOLARSHIP
TO CAMBRIDGE TO STUDY CLASSICS.
THAT'S WHAT GOT HIM INVITED
TO PREVIEW
THE MUSEUM'S NEW COLLECTION.
AND HE STOLE THE RING.
[sighs]
THAT WAS AN IMPULSIVE ACT.
HE'S NOT A THIEF.
HE'S A FOOLISH,
REBELLIOUS KID.
HE TOOK A COPY OF THE RING
IN WITH HIM.
IT WASN'T AN IMPULSIVE ACT.
IT WAS A PLAN.
HE'S NOT A THIEF.
YOU BELIEVE THAT,
AND THAT WAS YOUR PLAN.
IF YOU COULD
JUST TALK TO HIM,
HE'D RETURN THE RING,
BECAUSE HE'S...
AS YOU SAY, NOT A THIEF.
I COULD HAVE.
IF I MADE IT IN TIME,
I COULD HAVE DONE THAT.
AND NOW YOU TRACK DOWN
HIS KILLER
AND KILL THEM.
YEAH, WELL,
YOU KNOW HOW THAT WORKS.
I READ ALL ABOUT YOU,
MR. JANE.
I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
WELL,
YOU'LL END UP IN PRISON.
MAYBE.
BUT RIGHT NOW
I'M GONNA WALK OUT OF HERE,
AND YOU'RE GONNA LET ME.
OBVIOUSLY.
YOU'RE HOLDING A GUN,
AND I HAVE NO REAL REASON
TO STOP YOU.
THANKS FOR BEING SENSIBLE.
IT'S MY MIDDLE NAME.
[Patrick clears throat]
HEY.
I'M HAVING A PRIVATE WORD
WITH EVERYONE HERE
TO KINDA SET THE TONE.
COOL. IT'S, UH,
AN EXCELLENT PRACTICE.
HAVE A SEAT.
THANK YOU.
I SPOKE
TO LISBON YESTERDAY...MM-HMM.
TOLD HER HOW DEEPLY I VALUE
YOUR CONTRIBUTION TO THE BUREAU.
NICE TO HEAR.
I TOLD HER YOU'RE TOO GOOD
TO LOSE
TO SOME SMART-ASS MOVE
YOU MIGHT MAKE THAT TURNS BAD.
I TOLD HER THAT IF AND WHEN
IT HAPPENS, IT'S HER NECK.
YOU...
YOU'RE GOLDEN.
YOU'RE SAFE FOR ANYTHING
SHORT OF MURDER.
LISBON--NO.
YOU MESS UP,
SHE'S OUT OF HERE.
ANY QUESTIONS?
NOT THAT I CAN THINK OF
RIGHT NOW.
GOOD.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO WORKING WITH YOU.
LIKEWISE.
THANK YOU.
SEE YOU AROUND.
I KNEW THE PURCHASE WAS ILLEGAL.
I JUST DIDN'T WANT TO GET IN TROUBLE.
IRONIC. [chuckles]
WHERE'S THE GUN NOW?I HAVE NO IDEA. I HAVEN'T
SEEN IT SINCE THE SHOOT,
WHICH IS WHAT,
LIKE SIX WEEKS AGO?
I THOUGHT IT MIGHT BE
SOMEWHERE IN MY STUDIO,
BUT YOU GUYS WOULD HAVE
FOUND IT, I GUESS.
MAYBE SOMEBODY STOLE IT.THAT'S NOT VERY CREDIBLE.
IT'S THE TRUTH.
BOSS?YEAH.
I WAS GOING THROUGH THE FILES
ON BANKS' LAPTOP,
AND I FOUND THIS AND THIS
IN HIS TELEPHONE RECORDS.
CHO, YOU MIND?
ALL YOURS.
MR. BANKS, DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THE THEFT OF A RING
AT THE BRITISH MUSEUM?
CLEOPATRA'S WEDDING RING,
SUPPOSEDLY.
NO.
WHY?
WE CHECKED YOUR BROWSER HISTORY
ON YOUR OFFICE COMPUTER.
YOU LOOKED UP THE THEFT
OF THE RING TWO MONTHS AGO,
RIGHT AFTER YOU LET STANS
MOVE INTO YOUR POOL HOUSE.
DOWNLOADED QUITE A BIT
ABOUT IT.
I NEVER DID THIS.
YOU ALSO MADE
SEVERAL PHONE CALLS
TO A MAN NAMED LOUIS ANGLET,
WHO WE BELIEVE MAY HAVE
PURCHASED THE RING.
ANGLET?
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
THE CALLS ARE
IN YOUR PHONE RECORDS.
I PAID FOR OVERNIGHT DELIVERY.
I WAS TOLD GUARANTEED DELIVERY
BEFORE 10:00 A.M.
AND IT'S NOT HERE YET.
WELL, IF IT GETS HERE BY THEN
THAT'LL BE FINE. THANK YOU.
NO WORD ON SLOCOMBE?NEVER DESPAIR.
VAN PELT BRINGS HOPE.
UH, WE'VE BEEN TRACKING
THIS ANGLET GUY VIA CELL PHONE.
OFF THAT, WE GOT A BEAD
ON HIS CREDIT CARD.
THE THING IS, SOMEONE ELSE IS
TRACKING HIS PURCHASES AS WELL.
HAS TO BE SLOCOMBE.
AND AT 3:00 THIS AFTERNOON,
ANGLET HAS A MASSAGE BOOKED
AT THE BLUE WILLOW SPA, RIGHT
HERE IN DOWNTOWN SACRAMENTO.
MM-HMM. AND CHANCES ARE...
SLOCOMBE WILL SHOW UP.
SO GOOD.
I GOT ANGLET.
[sighs]
BOTTLE OF WATER, PLEASE.
[lowered voice] I SEE SLOCOMBE.
ANGLET?
WHAT?GOT A QUESTION FOR YOU.
OH, SORRY, I THINK YOU HAVE
THE WRONG GUY, BUT--HEY.DID YOU KILL MY BOY?
NO.DID YOU KILL MY BOY?
GET OFF ME![thud]
[Rigsby] CBI! ON THE GROUND![Cho] SLOCOMBE!
SLOCOMBE, DROP THE WEAPON!
[crowd screams]DROP IT!
[Slocombe grunts]
I JUST MEANT TO QUESTION HIM.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT CAME OVER ME.
I SAW RED.
I'LL END UP IN PRISON,
JUST LIKE YOU PREDICTED.
[scoffs] VERY FOOLISH.
NO.
IT'S HUMAN NATURE.
AH, IT MADE ME REALIZE
REVENGE IS NOT FOR ME.
POINTLESS. MORE VIOLENCE IS
JUST MORE VIOLENCE.
DOESN'T MAKE ANYTHING
ANY BETTER.
MM, MAYBE.
I'M NOT SO, UH...
YOU'RE BOOKED ON THE 8:00
TO LONDON TOMORROW MORNING.
TAKE IT, AND THERE'LL BE
NO CHARGES PENDING.THANK YOU.
I DON'T WANT TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
CLEAR?
OH, YES, MA'AM.
THANK YOU.
UH, TH-THAT'S MINE.
YEP.[pen clicks]
FRANCIS SLOCOMBE, THE MAN
WHO WAS TRYING TO KILL YOU--
WHY WAS THAT?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
WE KNOW THAT SLOCOMBE WAS TRACKING YOU.
WE KNOW THAT YOU CAME HERE FOR THE RING.
THIS RING MUST BE
VERY IMPORTANT.
ANGLET'S LAWYER'S HERE. EVERYONE HERE SEEMS
TO BE TALKING ABOUT IT.
WHAT KIND OF RING IS IT?AGENT LISBON.
EXCUSE ME.
[whistles and inhales sharply]
HE'S TOUGH.YEAH, WELL, THERE'S A REASON
WHY HE HASN'T BEEN IN JAIL.
THAT'S HIS ATTORNEY.
PROBABLY GETS ABOUT
$1,500 AN HOUR.
LET'S SPEND A LITTLE TIME
WITH HIM, RUN UP THE METER.
EXCUSE ME.
I'M AGENT LISBON.
WOULD YOU COME TO MY OFFICE
WITH ME, PLEASE? JUST UP HERE.
HI.
WHOA. YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE
MY LAWYER.
I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A COMPLIMENT.I'M NOT GONNA ANSWER
ANY MORE QUESTIONS.
NO MORE QUESTIONS.
I KNOW YOU DIDN'T KILL STANS.
YOU'RE TOO SMART FOR THAT.
BUT WHAT YOU DID DO IS YOU
BOUGHT CLEOPATRA'S WEDDING RING
FROM HIS KILLER.OH, THECLEOPATRA?
REALLY? QUEEN OF THE NILE,
THE BRIDE OF MARK ANTONY?
[increases volume] AND HERE'S WHAT YOU GOT--
ONE OF THESE...
$39 FAKIES.
CONSIDERABLY MORE IF YOU HAVE TO GET THE OVERNIGHT DELIVERY.
NOT YOUR FAULT.
NO REASON TO THINK
IT WAS A FAKE, OBVIOUSLY.
STANS DID STEAL THE RING.
THAT'S WHY
IT'S SUCH A GREAT SCAM.
HE CAN SELL THE SAME RING
OVER AND OVER.
NOW THE PERSON YOU BOUGHT
THE RING FOR--
I'M GUESSING THEY PAID MORE
THAN $39 FOR IT.
HOW MUCH DID THEY PAY FOR IT?
HUH?
$200,000?
MORE?
MORE THAN $200,000?
OHH.
I THINK
THEY'RE GONNA BE PRETTY MAD
WHEN THEY FIND OUT
IT'S A FAKE.
OHH! WHAT DO YOU THINK?
[laughs] OH, MAN.
YOU CAN GO NOW, MR. ANGLET.
YOUR ATTORNEY'S WAITING.
SEE YOU.
YOU STAY.
OH, I'M STAYING.
THE PHONE
AND INTERNET EVIDENCE SUGGESTS
THAT HOPPER KILLED STANS FOR
THE RING AND SOLD IT TO ANGLET.YES, IT DOES SUGGEST THAT.
SO YOU JUST PUT HOPPER
IN A GREAT DEAL OF DANGER.
[whispers] NAH.
[whispers] NAH?
[normal voice]
THAT'S YOUR CONSIDERED REPLY?
YEP.
PUT A GUARD ON HOPPER ASAP.WILL DO, BOSS.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS EXACTLY
THE KIND OF SCENARIO
WE TALKED ABOUT.HMM.
DIDN'T THINK
WE'D GET THERE SO SOON.
YOU BUTT IS ON THE LINE,
AGENT LISBON.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
PAID WAY TOO MUCH
FOR OVERNIGHT DELIVERY.
MAYBE WE SHOULD CONSIDER...
PROTECTIVE CUSTODY?
NO. NO WAY.I'LL PUT A TEAM TOGETHER, SIR.
FULL PROTECTION 24/7,
MY 4 BEST GUYS.
MR. BANKS,
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND--SURE, I DO. YOU PEOPLE CONVINCED
ANGLET THAT I CHEATED HIM,
AND THEN TURNED HIM LOOSE
TO KILL ME.
THAT PRETTY MUCH HOW IT GOES?YEAH, THAT'S--THAT'S
PRETTY MUCH HOW IT GOES.
BUT FOR THE RECORD,
AGENT LISBON HAD ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.JANE--
HOW GALLANT.IT WAS ALL MY IDEA.
A-AND WE COULD HAVE HELD ANGLET
IF YOU WERE MAN ENOUGH
TO ADMIT
SELLING HIM THE RING
IN THE FIRST PLACE.THAT'S IT. GET OUT.
YOU BETTER PRAY
NOTHING HAPPENS TO MY FAMILY.
[engine sputters]
OH, COME ON.
[grunts][grunts]
[both grunting]
WHERE IS IT?
I WANT THE REAL RING NOW.
[panting] WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT? I GAVE IT TO YOU.
YOU SOLD ME THE FAKE.
I WANT THE REAL ONE NOW.
I... I GAVE YOU THE REAL ONE,
ALL RIGHT?
TRUST ME. I PUT A GUN
IN THAT GUY'S FACE.
THERE'S NO WAY
HE'D HAND OVER A FAKE.
[sirens wail][Lisbon] PUT THE GUN DOWN!
[Rigsby] DROP THE GUN!ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
HEY, WHAT DID I DO?
I JUST HELPED YOU CATCH
THE GUY. ALL RIGHT, RELAX.ON THE GROUND!
[Van Pelt] PUT YOUR HANDS
ON YOUR HEAD.LET'S SEE YOUR HANDS.
UP AGAINST THE TRUCK, BANDINO.
GO! GO!
LET'S SEE YOUR HANDS.
VICTOR BANDINO,
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDER OF OLIVER STANS.
YEAH, YOU THINK
BEING A COP'S STRESSFUL?
TRY BEING A COP IN PRISON,
JERK.
[police radio chatter]
I KNOW MY JOB.
I DO GOOD BACKGROUND CHECKS.
I FOUND OUT THAT SMITHSON
WAS REALLY STANS,
FOUND OUT ABOUT THE RING.
I APPROACHED HIM.
WE TALKED.
HE COULDN'T SELL THE RING.
IT WAS TOO HOT.
BUT I KNOW SOME PEOPLE
WHO KNOW SOME PEOPLE
THAT PUT ME IN TOUCH
WITH ANGLET, AND THAT WAS IT.
I BROKERED THE DEAL.
WHY'D YOU KILL STANS?
HE CHANGED HIS MIND.
DIDN'T WANT TO SELL IT.
AT THE LAST MINUTE,
THE IDIOT WANTED TO CONFESS,
RETURN IT TO THE MUSEUM.
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED TO DO?
YOU SHOT HIM.
I HAD NO CHOICE.
IT WAS
A SPUR OF THE MOMENT THING.
RIGHT. NO PREMEDITATION,
NO DEATH PENALTY.
THE ONLY THING?
YOU PLANNED AHEAD.
YOU PLANTED THE PHONE
AND INTERNET EVIDENCE
ON HOPPER BANKS.
THAT DOESN'T LOOK GOOD.
BYE, SON.
OKAY.
WELL, IT APPEARS I WAS...
WRONG ABOUT YOUR SON.
HE WASN'T A THIEF.
HE WANTED TO RETURN THE RING.
ANGLET CUT A DEAL,
TRADED FOR HIS FREEDOM.
WAY OF THE WORLD.
YEAH. IT DOESN'T FEEL
ANY BETTER.
KNOWING WHO KILLED HIM,
KNOWING HE'LL BE PUNISHED--
IT DOESN'T MAKE
A DAMN BIT OF DIFFERENCE.
I THOUGHT IT WOULD.
BUT THIS...
IS WHAT HE WANTED.
I CAN GIVE THAT TO HIM NOW,
THANKS TO YOU.
EH.
WELL,
I BETTER NOT MISS MY PLANE.
TIME TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
YEAH. GOOD-BYE.
I WASN'T GONNA HUG YOU.
I KNOW. JUST MAKING SURE.
[Lisbon] OH, NO.[Patrick] THERE WAS
A CERTAIN VULNERABILITY,
A CERTAIN RUMPLED GENTLENESS
TO HIM.
VULNERABILITY?
MM, I THOUGHT SO.
YEAH.
COMFORTABLE?
I'M GETTING THERE, YEAH.
REGARDING
AGENTS RIGSBY AND VAN PELT--
THEY'RE
IN A ROMANTIC RELATIONSHIP.
WELL, I...
WELL, ROMANTIC?
YOU'RE TOO GOOD OF A COP
NOT TO HAVE NOTICED,
AND SINCE YOU HAVEN'T DONE
ANYTHING ABOUT IT,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
TAKE ACTION MYSELF.
JUST WANTED
TO LET YOU KNOW FIRST.
GOOD NIGHT.
SHE'S GOOD.
STAY TUNED FOR SCENES
FROM OUR NEXT EPISODE.